Guide to the Stanford University, Department of English, Honors Theses
Stanford University Libraries.
- Theses, Accession ARCH-1993-088
  - Christopher, Noam Jesse, The Curve of an Emotion: Identity in James Joyce's Fiction., May 1992 (Box 1)
  - Cini, Carol F., Edith Wharton's Challenge of Sex Roles in The Age of Innocence., April 1986 (Box 1)
  - Claymon, Deborah S., "Long Day's Journey Into Night": From Script to Film., May 1992 (Box 1)
  - Cordero, Edward M., Out of the Wasteland: A Comparative Study of the impetus behind postwar Japanese and Americna poetry., May 1991 (Box 1)
  - Cudjoe, Frances L., A Reading of the Constructed Identities and Women-Centered Relationships in Brown Girl, Brownstones and Sula., May 1992 (Box 1)
  - Dosanjh, Rajit S., The Occasional Chaucer; Epistolarity and Authorial Presence in Chaucer's Short Poems and Troilus and Criseyde., May 1993 (Box 1)
  - Dow, Joshua, The Awakening to the Unconscious: Kate Chopin and the Development of Eros and Psyche., 1992-1993 (Box 1)
  - Drimmer, Jonathan, Man -- Mark Twain's Mysterious Stranger: A Demystification of Man and the universe in The Mysterious Stranger Manuscripts., April 1990 (Box 1)
  - Elgart, Jodi Lynn, Who Writes Whom?: Lyn Hejinian and the Politics of Media Review., May 1993 (Box 1)
  - Elia, Oriana, Chaos Vanquished: Order Within Multiplicity in Virginia Woolf's Mrs. Dalloway., April 1986 (Box 1)
  - Fagel, Brian, This is a Very Queer Place Certainly: A Comparative Analysis of Flann O'Brien's At Swim-Two-Birds and Felipe Alfau's Locos: A Comedy of Gestures., 1991 (Box 1)
  - Field, Corinne, Tradition and the Feminist Talent: Adrienne Rich's Ideological Re-Vision of T. S. Eliot., May 1987 (Box 1)
  - Fine, Douglas J., Telos at Chaos: Writing Jorge Louis Borges., May 1992 (Box 1)
  - Fu, Lisa J., Women Warriors: Female Rebellion in Kingston's The Woman Warrior and Walker's The Color Purple., Spring 1993 (Box 1)
  - Geary, Stephen W., The theory of Mimetic Desire as a Key to Henry Handel Richardons' Ultima Thule., Spring 1990 (Box 1)
  - Gelpi, Albert, Doubleness and Center: Consciousness in the Works of Katherine Anne Porter., May 1991 (Box 1)
  - Glouberman, Robert, Existential Motifs in Faulkner's Novels. (Box 1)
  - Grabowski, Douglas, The Delivery of the hero: Men writing fiction in the novels of jane Austen., 1987 (Box 1)
  - Gravitz, Deborah, "Even out of Your Report": Narrative Compromise in Three Shakespeare Romances., May 1987 (Box 1)
  - Hansen, Peri Z., Byron: Poet, Statesman, Philhellene., May 1988 (Box 2)
  - Headrick, Lora Dawn, "A Kind of Grief and Pity": Great Expectations, Absalom, Absalom! and Visions of Narrative Forgiveness., May 1990 (Box 2)
  - Helmich, Bo, The Language of Incarnation: patterns of meaning in some short stories of Flannery O'Connor., May 1992 (Box 2)
  - Hildebrant, Natascha, "Powerful, Feminine, Maternal Hands": Androgyny and the Women in Middlemarch., April 1989 (Box 2)
  - Hope, Miranda, The Right to Speak and the Theatrical Dimensions of Virginia Woolf., May 1993 (Box 2)
  - Huerta, Amelia M., The allegory of the Mass and the "Pardoner's Tale"., May 1988 (Box 2)
  - Itoi, Anna, Clothing as Coded Language in The Mill on the Floss and Vanity Fair., May 1991 (Box 2)
  - Jeffrey, Margaret M., A place from which to speak, a place from which to write: conflicts of cultural identity in Leslie Marmon Silko's Ceremony and the Poetry of Wendy Rose., Spring 1989 (Box 2)
  - Jennifer Lanoff, "And Live Like Solomon": W. B. Yeats and the poetics of desire., May 1993 (Box 2)
  - Jones, Ceri, The sensual world int he mind's eye: James Joyce's Ulysses and the language of visuality., April 1990 (Box 2)
  - Jones, Michael, What are Poets For?: Considering Heidegger's Question, and some Responses from Adrienne Rich and John Ashbery., May 1988 (Box 2)
  - Kalter, Susan, Rocks that talk like gods: Narrative structure and the voices of women in Bessie Head's Maru and Myriam Warner-Vieyra's Juletane., May 1991 (Box 2)
  - Karagueuzian, Catherine, "So rare a wondered father and a wife": Prospero's subjugation of Miranda in The Tempest., May 1991 (Box 2)
  - Kemker, Aimee, Sifting through the ashes: a study of Sir Thomas Malory's Le Morte D'Arthur and Walter Percy's Lancelot., April 1989 (Box 2)
  - Kent, Le'a, Textual interplay and the status of the self: three women's autobiographies of insanity, 1956-1974., April 1990 (Box 2)
  - Kinch, Sean, Between the ticks of the clock: Heraldic universe in The Alexandrian Quartet., April 1990 (Box 2)
  - Kirazian, Lisa, Place, Space, and Boundary: The Journey's of Anne Elliot in Jane Austen's Persuasion., May 1992 (Box 2)
  - Klingsporn, Gregory K., The discourse of dystopia: a Foucaltian study of sexuality in the dystopic novels of Aldous Huxley and George Orwell., May 1992 (Box 2)
  - Landau, Deborah, "A City Made of Chains": The psychological demands of culture as explored in Anne Sexton's play, Mercy Street., April 1989 (Box 2)
  - Landon, Robert, Fitzgerald's Trinity: REader, anarrator, Hero, and a mystery of Mysteries., May 1991 (Box 2)
  - Lau, Sarah J., Gender and Ethnicity in Maxine Hong Kingston's Woman Warrior., 1987-1988 (Box 2)
  - Lee, Christine, Silence in Hardy's A Pair of Blue Eyes., April 1986 (Box 2)
  - Leichter, James Jensen, Daring pilots in extremity: John Dryden and Anthony Ashley Cooper, the First Earl of Shaftesbury. A Study of Absalom and Achitophel., May 1988 (Box 2)
  - Liau, Chiamin Corii, A photographic plate and a broken cinema: filmic influences in William Faulkner's Absalom, Absalom!., May 1993 (Box 2)
  - Lodato, Amy A., The transcendental poet: gender and metaphysics in Elizabeth Barrett Browning's "Aurora Leigh". (Box 2)
  - Lopez-Aguado, Susan, Ideological Implications of Jane Austen's Persuasion: conservative criticism of the aristocracy in a regency world., April 1990 (Box 2)
  - Lopez, Elizabeth, Harrowing Clods: A Study of the Relationship between man and nature in the works of Thomas Hardy., June 1992 (Box 2)
  - Lundgren, Nicholas D., Ecological re-visions of Humanity in Nature: a reading of Jean Toomer's Cane and William Faulkner's Go Down, Moses from a Radical Ecological Perspective., May 1993 (Box 2)
  - Magowan, Kimberly, J. D. Salinger's Sensitive Hero: Seymour Glass as Fragile Seer., June 5, 1989 (Box 3)
  - Mallery, Kathleen, A Key to Eudora Welty: Objects Unlock the Inner World., April 1988 (Box 3)
  - Mann, Julie A., The painter and the word: reading Charles Demuth., May 1990 (Box 3)
  - Manzulli, Mia, Social mobility in Old New York: the social context of Edith Wharton's novels of Manners., March 1989 (Box 3)
  - Martin, Tera, 160, 372 and counting...: The literary response to AIDS., March 1993 (Box 3)
  - Martinez, Michele, Forces of Exile in James Joyce's A Portrait of the Artist as a Young Man and Ulysses: Character and the Dramatic Narrative., April 1990 (Box 3)
  - Meyercord, Christopher, Quentin Compson: William Faulkner's avatar of the frustrated lover., March 1992 (Box 3)
  - Mohalley, Jacqueline, Conrad's political women: a study of Nostromo and Under Western Eyes., April 1992 (Box 3)
  - Mohlenhoff, Jennifer, Retelling Violence: Public Riot and Private Lives in Charles Dickens's Barnaby Rudge and Honore de Balzac's L'envers de L'Histoire Contemporaine., May 1991 (Box 3)
  - Murphy, Joseph C., Flannery O'Connor and the Anagogical Imaginiation., Spring 1987 (Box 3)
  - Nedrow, Jeff, Between Perfectionism and Criticism: John Steinbeck's Search for Stylistic Identity., May 1989 (Box 3)
  - Neimann, Paul Grafton, Jr., Creative Violence: Tristram Shandy and the aphilosophy of Wit., May 1993 (Box 3)
  - Olsen, Erica, "Hidden Meaning on the Surface": The Composition of Nathaniel Hawthorne's Marble Faun., May 1988 (Box 3)
  - Palmberg, Elizabeth, Reading Henry James' What Maisie Knew: What He Represents, Who She is Not, and Who She Becomes., May 1992 (Box 3)
  - Palmer, Lisa, Emasculated Males and Affirmative Females: The Dispossessed in Athol Fugard's Port Elizabeth Plays., April 1986 (Box 3)
  - Palmer, Sharon, Song of Wittman Ah Sing: Tripmaster Monkey: His Fake Book as a Novel of the Historical Emergence of Man., April 1990 (Box 3)
  - Peng, Shih-Wei, Wuthering Heights and Emily Bronte's Vision of Childhood., May 1990 (Box 3)
  - Peyser, Marc, The Destruction of Old Women in America: How Society Defeats the Individual in Wharton, Porter, Faulkner, and McCullers., April 1986 (Box 3)
  - Pierce, Todd, The Eye at the Window: A Study of Narrative Consciousness in the Gothic Novel., April 1990 (Box 3)
  - Pinckert, Eric, Ernest Hemingway and the Process of Omission., April 1989 (Box 3)
  - Polhemus, Mack, The Textual Character in Shakespear's Sonnets., May 1987 (Box 3)
  - Ponce, Margo, Lorna Dee Cervantes and the confessional poets: an exploration of Cervantes' work as related to Confessional Poets Robert Lowell and Anne Sexton., June 1990 (Box 3)
  - Price, Hilary, Mother/land: Conceptions of Home and Self in the Fiction of Jamaica Kincaid., May 1992 (Box 3)
  - Przybylko, Eric J., The Rise of the "Angry Young Man": male adolescent perspectives in the fiction of Dickens, Joyce, and Salinger., May 1993 (Box 3)
  - Quan, Gail, Emily Bronte's vision of childhood and its influence on children;'s literature., May 1990 (Box 3)
  - Reed, Laura, Ekphrasis and Meaning: A study of two Renaissance texts., Spring 1989 (Box 3)
  - Regensburg, Kenneth, World and desire in the lives of writings of Henry James and Ernest Hemingway., Spring 1993 (Box 3)
  - Reilly, Robin, Jack Kerouac: the "Whoopeeing Soul" encounters the timeless text of bliss., May 1992 (Box 3)
  - Richard, Andy, "The Evermore Becoming": the painting and the novel in the works of Thomas Hardy., May 1991 (Box 3)
  - Roffman, Karin, Anger and politics in Virginia Woolf's novel: The Waves., May 1992 (Box 3)
  - Roldan, Leslie Ann, Curiosity. Domination. Death. Female Sexuality in Angela Carter's "The Bloody Chamber."., 1992 (Box 3)
  - Roupe, Thomas Allen, Observations on artistic creation: An essay on subjective perception and reality in Impressionist fiction and painting., 1986-1987 (Box 3)
  - Rowland, Joshua C., A fugitive perfection: the ideal of the American artist in the fiction of Herman Melville., April 1990 (Box 3)
  - Saenz, Cynthia, Consolation in "The Bok of the Duchess" and "Pearl": A Poetical Process., May 1990 (Box 4)
  - Schirmer, Elizabeth, Text, context, and the process of reading "Sir Gawain and the Green Knight"., June 1993 (Box 4)
  - Sehdev, Indra, Prairie Women in fiction and History: 1850-1930., April 1987 (Box 4)
  - Shannon, Jonathan Holt, Much more the better for being a little bad: A study of Sir Gawain and chivalry in the Middle Ages., May 1988 (Box 4)
  - Shapiro, Donna, Psychotics and simpletons, mythic maidens and matrons: A Reading of Faulkner's The Sound and the Fury and As I Lay Dying., Winter 1986 (Box 4)
  - Sheehan, Cathleen, Jacob's Room: Virginia Woolf's new form for a new novel., April 16, 1990 (Box 4)
  - Shelton, Dylan M., Quest for universal peace: The medieval orientation towards a principial sovereignty. (Box 4)
  - Siminoff, David E., The novel transformed., March 1986 (Box 4)
  - Stewart, Catherine, The Splitting Image of Myself: Seeing Suture in Ingmar Bergman's Persona., May 1988 (Box 4)
  - Synn, Theresa J., Feminism, hysteria, and coping with reality: Henrik Ibsen's "A Doll's House," "Hedda Gabler," and "The Lady from the sea."., June 1992 (Box 4)
  - Tandon, Geetika, Writing across the lines: the essay in the university., May 1991 (Box 4)
  - Tobin, Adam, The inprovised Chaucer: literary improvisation in the Canterbury Tales: the invitation to create in Chaucer's structure and openness and the script of "The Canterbury Tales, An Improvised Journey"., May 1993 (Box 4)
  - Tweedie, James, The Written Image: Alain Robbe-Grillet, "Last Year at Marienbad," and the "Poetic" cinema. (Box 4)
  - Verchick, Robert, The best of life and the shortest: Play and laughter in Tom, Huck, and No. 44., April 1986 (Box 4)
  - Villanueva, Valerie, Understanding Shakespeare's Women: A source study of The Merchant of Venice, Measure for Measure, and The Winter's Tale., May 1990 (Box 4)
  - Waff, Emily E., The Phenomenology of Virginia Woolf's Fiction: a look at two novels, via the philosophy of Martin Heidegger., May 1990 (Box 4)
  - White, Verania, The juxtaposition of thematically opposite symbols in W. B. Yeats' texts for the theatre: a Critical analysis of The Countess Cathleen and Purgatory., Spring 1990 (Box 4)
  - Whitley, Ann, Keat's "Lamia": A Medical Case of Love-Melancholy., April 1986 (Box 4)
  - Willburn, Sarah, Parrots, passions, pinks: Intertextuality, Catholicism, and spiritualism in Kate Chopin's The Awakening., May 1991 (Box 4)
  - Wilson, Clint, Child-like, Child Life: A Study of Children in the Fiction of Charles Dickens., 1987 (Box 4)
  - Wilson, David S., Coruscations or The Lantern Quest., May 1992 (Box 4)
  - Wiltz, Melanie, The Realities of West Indian Life As Depictd By Emigrating Authors of the Mid-Twentieth Century. (Box 4)
  - Wong, David P. C., Between Disbelief and Wonder: Magic Realism in Contemporary Fiction., November 1990 (Box 4)
  - Wong, Sabrina, Was this a poet?, May 1993 (Box 4)
  - Woodcock, Heather, Crafting contradictions: the ideas of order in the poetic voices of Wallace Stevens., April 1989 (Box 4)
  - Yarbro, Caroline, A Silence is broken: the supernatural in the poetry of Thomas Hardy and W. B. Yeats., May 1992 (Box 4)
  - Youngdahl, Karie, "Like a shot in the film": Writing and representation in Doris Lessing's The Golden Notebook., May 1987 (Box 4)
  - Yuspa, Catherine M., "There's No Place Like Home": The Wizard of Oz as a reaction against the turn-of-the-century women's movement., May 1992 (Box 4)
- Theses, Accession ARCH-2011-152
  - Auyoung, Elaine, The pleasure of understanding: characterization of the reader in the early novels of Jane Austen., 2003 (Box 1)
  - Bennett, Chad, Greene/Hitchcock: statements of faith., 1998 (Box 1)
  - Chang, Catherine Ming Yee, Oscar Wilde's moral presence in his major plays: a study in revisions., 1998 (Box 1)
  - Elliott, Chiyuma, Locating La Virgen: representations of La Virgen de Guadalupe in contemporary Chicana literature., 1996 (Box 1)
  - Gellene, Tara, Stranger than fiction: towards a practical definition of what it means to read "Fiction"., 2002 (Box 1)
  - Graves, Jennifer, William Carlos Williams, Marcel Duchamp, and Dada: the art of the anti-artist., 1996 (Box 1)
  - Hilke, Kevin, "Information machines": anticipation of new media ecologies and the proto-new media subject in Thomas Pynchon's The Crying of Lot 49., 2007 (Box 1)
  - Peterson, Kate, Medbh McGuckian: a poem written from a kitchen conversation., 1996 (Box 1)
  - Roldan, Leslie Ann, Curiosity, domination, death: female sexuality in Angela Carter's "The Bloody Chamber"., 1992 (Box 1)
  - Richieri, Cristina M., La vie d'une femme: Charlotte Brontë and the "still life" narrative in Villette., 2007 (Box 2)
  - Seelig, Adam G., Beckett's dying remains: the creative process in the works of Samuel Beckett., 1997 (Box 2)
  - Silver, James, "How to live, what to do": a study of two poet-professionals (Wallace Stevens and William Carlos Williams)., 1997 (Box 2)
  - Sydow, Nora Christiana, Verbal and visual form in the satire of James Thurber and Walt Kelly., 2006 (Box 2)
  - Triplett, Jodi, Misconceptions of The Lord of the Rings., 1996 (Box 2)
  - Tyler, Dennis, Transcending racial compositions: an analysis of character identity in Jean Toomer's Cane., 2002 (Box 2)
  - Walton, Leslie Anne, "In the position of teacher": erotic pedagogy in the works of George Eliot., 1996 (Box 2)
  - Wilnai, Sigal, The morality of comic entertainment and the problems of miscommunication in the comedies of Frances Burney., 1996 (Box 2)
  - Younge, Phineas (Michael), Outside the boundaries., 1996 (Box 2)
  - Donovan, Daniel Kemper, The novel, the play: distinct artistic genres in Wilkie Collins's The Woman in White., 2001 (Box 3)
  - Fox, Reneé, Empires of the imagination: Egypt and Fin de Siècle fictions of imperialism., 1999 (Box 3)
  - Park, Samuel, Maurice: the closet and coming out., 1998 (Box 3)
  - Richie, Bradley, A second creation: translating André Verdet., 2001 (Box 3)
  - Sandusky, Shelley J., A search for independence: Henry Fielding as dramatist, novelist, magistrate, and editor., 1988 (Box 3)
  - Shields, Andrew, On the border: structures of identify in the novels of Milan Kundera., 1987 (Box 3)
  - Chang, Catherine Ming Yee, Oscar Wilde's moral presence in his major plays: a study in revisions., 1998 (Box 3)
  - Ridgeway, Eliza, A princess' primer: literary fairy tales and the rule of manners., 2005 (Box 3)
  - Roedder, Erica, Causation in explanation: some adventures of Goldilocks., 2001 (Box 3)
  - Tseng, Jennifer, Mitsuye Yamada and Nellie Wong: poetry, politics, identity: connections., 1990 (Box 4)
  - Tobin, Adam, The improvised Chaucer: literary improvisation in the Canterbury Tales: the invitation to create in Chaucer's structure and openness; and the script of "the Canterbury Tales, an improvised journey"., 1993 (Box 4)
  - Chua, Lusan Clarissa, Dancing without dancing: the social politics of ballroom dance in the novels of Jane Austen., 1997 (Box 4)
  - Christopher, Noam Jesse, The curve of an emotion: identity in James Joyce's fiction., 1992 (Box 4)
  - Quigley, Megan M., Re-visioning T. S. Elliot's Four Quartets: Adrienne Rich's Atlas of the Difficult World., 1995 (Box 4)
  - Dosanjh, Rajit S., The occasional Chaucer: epistolarity and authorial presence in Chaucer's short poems and Troilus and Criseyde., 1993 (Box 4)
  - Chuang, Angie, Mediating the 'battle between art and profit': the artistic-commercial divide and Brechtian aesthetics in the Joseph Losey-Harold Pinter relationship., 1995 (Box 4)
  - Gordon, Katherine H., In the alchemist's workshop: an exploration of the drafts of four poems by Louise Brogan., 1995 (Box 4)
  - Singler, Jennifer Marie, Heroism, empire and language: Joseph Conrad's linguistic exploration., 1995 (Box 4)
  - Levin, Jon, Tragedy and the writings of Norman Maclean., 1994 (Box 5)
  - Pifer, Melissa, An annunciation: Christina Rossetti's Goblin Market and the female adolescent perspective., 1994 (Box 5)
  - Lopez, Alicia, An increase of life: the fruits of marriage in Jane Austen's novels., 2000 (Box 5)
  - Harvey, Christina D., Imagining aboriginal realities: the poetry of Anita Heiss and Lisa Bellear., 2002 (Box 5)
  - Choi, Karine, "I had been hungry, all the years": the aesthetics of anorexia in the hunger poems of Emily Dickinson and Louise Glück., 1998 (Box 5)
  - Huggins, Teri, T. S. Eliot's shifting anxieties: the changing portrayal of women in Eliot's poetry., 1996 (Box 5)
  - Kasper, Sari Jane, Mirrors, cloaks, and corridors: schizophrenia as metaphor in Janet Frame's Faces in the Water and Jennifer Dawson's The Ha-Ha., 1994 (Box 5)
  - Chow, Christopher, Charles Dickens' immoral fairground: the grotesque realism of The Old Curiosity Shop., 1995 (Box 5)
  - Hokanson, Chris Harold, The art of detection: redefining critical understanding of detective novel addition., 1995 (Box 5)
  - Dungy, Camille, Revolutions in literature: the poetry of Nikki Giovanni., 1995 (Box 5)
  - Dunne, Sarah A., J. M. Coetzee: an examination of the political responsibility of a white writer in South Africa., 1994 (Box 5)
  - Buchanan, Katherine, This is America reconstructed: tradition, turmoil, and American literature textbooks since 1965., 2004 (Box 6)
  - Jensen, Ashly, Exploring the abyss: Emily Brontë, D. H. Lawrence, and sadomasochism as a means of achieving ideal love., 1997 (Box 6)
  - Krauss, Nicole, Dead radio., 1996 (Box 6)
  - Henry, Nancy, "Remember Lot's wife": parsing a Biblical sentence., 1987 (Box 6)
  - Liu, Jennifer, Writing home: the structure of melancholia in Shirley Geok-lin Lim's Among the White Moon Faces., 2008 (Box 6)
  - Lukin, Tanya Marie, Night Wind Women: Native American women's poetry as performance., 1998 (Box 6)
  - Lee, Suzanne S., A tale of her own: Zora Neale Hurston, her folk, and her audience., 1994 (Box 6)
  - Pastuszek, Danya Smith, Methodical Wright: conceptions of poverty in Native Son., 2003 (Box 6)
  - Snyder, Ryan, Coming to terms: interracial relationships, psychic politics and self-critical discourses through Willa Cather's The Professor's House., 1998 (Box 6)
  - Olsson, Katherine, Samson's disease and cure: adaptations of humoral and paracelsian medical philosophies in Milton's Samson Agonistes., 1997 (Box 6)
  - Kao, Jennifer, Reading lessons: placing Mary Sidney in literary history., 1998 (Box 6)
  - Pérez, Sarah Emily, Geography: the world throught "I" of Elizabeth Bishop., 1998 (Box 6)
  - Trew, Heather Marie, A murder most horrid: an analysis of morality, sensationalism and genre in the case of Eliza Fales and Jason Fairbanks., 1997 (Box 7)
  - Kim, Leslie, (M)other (M)orality: mourning in the fairy tales of Lucy Lane Clifford., 1998 (Box 7)
  - Remington, Bridget, Dirty old man, or genius of the crowd: the perpetual outsider, Charles Bukowski., 1996 (Box 7)
  - Meyers, Jill, "I won't go back to it": poetry of place and place-making in Eavan Boland and Nuala Ní Dhomhnaill., 1998 (Box 7)
  - Scott, Ramsey, The excarnation: a fabricated unearthing; an experimental thesis on the poetry of Robert Duncan., 1999 (Box 7)
  - Noguchi, Irene, Charles Dickens' Great Expectations: the language of the novel and the film., 2002 (Box 7)
- Theses, Accesssion 2015-039
  - Ayala-Hurtado, Elena, Mistresses, maids, and maternalism: representations of gendered cross-class relationships in Victorian British writing, 1834-1901., 2014 May 12 (Box 1)
  - Weston, Sarah T., They laugh at our play: William Blake's a Theater of the Mind., 2014 (Box 1)